christopher wood

Full Stack Web Developer

Contact



? Phone 704.497.9263

✓ Email ctwood89@gmail.com

• Location Charlotte, NC

□ Web www.woodchristopher.com

Tech



THILL Strong

E CSS Knowledgable

Js JavaScript Strong

React Strong

nede Node.Js Strong

MySQL Knowledgable

MongoDB Knowledgeable

Python Knowledgeable

Python KnowledgeableAdobe CS Knowledgeable

Social



in LinkedIn /cwood89

Github /cwood89

(i) Instagram /thenocturnalcoder

About Me



I am a recent graduate of the Full Stack Coding Boot-camp at UNC Charlotte. Throughout the bootcamp I had to maintain a full time job working nights to support my family and cared for my 2 year old daughter in the mornings while her mother was at work. Without any days off and sacrificing every second of my free time I made it through and developed a passion for coding.

I've spent the last two years working as a perishable order selector for Harris Teeter. It's a fast paced environment to say the least and communication is crucial. This has taught me to be efficient and find creative ways to solve problems. Which in turn has made me one to the top performers in my position.

As a natural problem solver and self-learner, I'd make a great asset and would immediately bring value to any team.

>_

Projects

Giftastic - https://cwood89.github.io/GifTastic/

- Allows users to search for gifs. Uses Iquery to perform ajax calls to the giphy api.
- Sole Contributor
- · Made with JQuery.
- See Code: https://github.com/cwood89/GifTastic

Real Solution - https://powerful-tor-47566.herokuapp.com/

- Real estate investment app made to find the best valued properties based on desired investment yield.
- My responsibilities included: Server side authentication, user database functionality, login functionality including password encryption and page routing and redirects.
- Made with React, React-Router, Axios, Express, Express-Session, Bcrypt, and Sequelize.
- See Code: https://github.com/cwood89/RealSolution

Head Lights - https://head-lights.herokuapp.com/

- Web scraping app that allows users to read and save sports articles.
- Sole Contributor
- Made with Handlebars, Express, Axios, Cherio, and Mongoose.
- See Code: https://github.com/cwood89/headLights

React Book Search - https://react-book-club-cw.herokuapp.com/

- Book search app which uses the google books API to search for and save books.
- Sole Contributor
- Made with the MERN stack: MongoDb, Express, React, Node.
- See Code: https://github.com/cwood89/react-book-search



Professional Experience

Perishable Order Selector

Oct 2016 - Present Charlotte, NC

- Quickly reached required productivity standards after hire.
- Work with a team of 50 employes to ensure shipping is completed successfully and efficiently.
- Chosen to train new associates after only 6 months on the job.
- Was an asset in multiple departments including management.

Assistant Manager Party City

May 2009 - Oct 2016 Los Angeles, CA - Charlotte, NC

- Started as a part-time associate and advanced through multiple promotions.
- Interviewed, hired and trained new staff.
- Handled store inventory including ordering, transferring and counting product.
- Counted cash drawers and made bank deposits.



Education

The Coding Boot Camp at UNC Charlotte

Sept 2018 - April 2019

- 6 month-long intensive web development boot camp.
- Technologies covered include: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, MySQL, Sequelize, Node.Js, MongoDB, Mongoose, .Net.
- Completed multiple full-stack projects, with a focus on the MERN stack.
- Individual and group work.
- Pair programming.

Calfornia State Northridge

Aug 2007 - June 2009

• Completed 2 years towards a degree in Mechanical Engineering.